Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Arts and Cultural Left TAM.540
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Arts and Cultural Left
2009-present
TAM.540
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
45.0 websites and 209.8 GB.
The Left, in addition to having its own culture(s), including its own cultural institutions, has expressed its views through the arts, both collectively, and individually. Views of the political role of the arts range from the utilitarian (agtiprop, etc.) to the transformative (Surrealism, etc.). This web archive contains websites of (principally) U.S. entities involved in left artistic or cultural activity and criticism. The Arts are understood to include all the individual arts: music, literature, motion pictures, painting, sculpture, theater, etc. Websites relating to the use of mass media in connection with the arts are also included, as are websites devoted to left satire and humor. Left cultural activity involves efforts to radically critique transform culture, and cultural attitudes, in part or as a whole. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Tamiment Library.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library (Labor and the Left) Web Archive: Arts and the Cultural Left Web Archive was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Arrangement
Arranged Alphabetically.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
This web archive contains websites of (principally) U.S. entities involved in left artistic or cultural activity and criticism. The Arts are understood to include all the individual arts: music, literature, motion pictures, painting, sculpture, theater, etc. Websites relating to the use of mass media in connection with the arts are also included, as are websites devoted to left satire and humor. Left cultural activity involves efforts to radically critique transform culture, and cultural attitudes, in part or as a whole. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Related Archival Materials
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the web page Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Arts |x Political aspects |z United States.; Arts |z United States.; Political satire, American.
- "Activist Poets' Roundtable with Dennis Brutus, 5/2/2011-
- Adbusters Culterjammer Headquarters: Journal of the Mental Environment, 11/26/2010-
- Andyland Art & Activism, 7/19/2010-
- Artists Against the War NYC, 8/16/2009-
- Billy Bragg - Activism, 12/1/2010-
- Cuban Art Space, 12/3/2010-
- DeeDee Halleck, 10/28/2011-
- Design Action Collective, 11/05/11-
- d.u.m.b.A collective, 12/9/2009-
- Ecoartivismo, 12/8/2011-
- Graphic Witness, 9/8/2009-
- graphix4change.com, 11/3/2009-
- Guernica Magazine, 10/27/2009-
- Inkworks Press, 11/05/2011-
- Justseeds, 5/19/2011-
- Milton Rogovin, Social Documentary Photographer, 9/8/2010-
- Northern Sun, 7/8/2011-
- Northland Poster Collective, 6/13/2011-
- Not an Alternative, 2/13/2012-
- Radical Art Caucus, 11/3/2009-
- Strike Anywhere, 5/2/2011-
- Surveillance Camera Players, 7/27/2011-
- Terranode
- Theater for the New City, 10/06/2011-
- The Design Studio for Social Intervention, 6/1/2011-
- The Fugs, 7/13/2010-
- The Funniest Signs From The Rally To Restore Sanity And/Or Fear!, 11/13/2010-
- The Groundswell Collective, 11/5/2009-
- The Yes Men, 11/3/2009-
- Transnational Temps Art Collective, 12/9/2011-
- We Are Many TV, 12/4/2011-
- Working Theater, 10/14/2009-
- World War 3 Illustrated, 8/12/2010-